Okay, so this is a theoretical question.
If Nat Turner and his band of slaves who were revolting,
if after decades of torture, dehumanization, rape,
watching their friends and their families killed,
their entire lives being controlled by other human beings
who do not consider them to be worthy of even having basic amenities,
if in their revolt they harmed people,
they harmed folks who were not slave owners,
would they be terrorists?
I would say yes.
If we are viewing terrorism as a tactic without judgment,
I mean, there are a number of ways to attack, right?
There is violent terrorism.
There is passive resistance.
There is, you know, there is peaceful protest.
There is media.
There are a number of ways to attack a situation.
And a terrorist approach is one method.
The problem is that we do not use the term without judgment.
The problem is that we only use the term terrorist
when we are somehow identifying eruptions of violence by the oppressed
in response to their oppressor.
We seem to have all types of vocabulary for chronic subjugation,
for chronic discrimination, oppression.
We have all types of vocabulary that we come up with for that
for a number of nations,
whether it be America in the present or in the past,
whether it be Israel, whether it be Russia.
We come up with a number of different ways to find language
for making that different than terrorism.
But it is no different.
The only difference is who gets to tell the story of what happened.
And I just want to say one more thing,
because in this country,
you notice how they don't never want to use the word terrorist
to describe the actual behaviors
of these white people who be terrorizing folks.
They don't.
They don't never want to use that term
because that term is only reserved
for passing judgment on people
who are responding to their oppressor
in the way that their oppressor has been treating them.
Yes.
Because the reality is that
if it were just being acknowledged as a tactic,
then it should be used as it is applicable to the situation.
And you can't tell me
that these white people walking up in tops in Buffalo,
walking up in the church in North Carolina
and killing all these people
is not terrorism.
It is absolutely terrorism,
but they don't use it
because they only reserve it for people like us.
No, for those people,
they call it mental health.
You know why?
They call it mental health
because in their minds,
they're like,
well, this person must be crazy
to have deployed this behavior.
And they're somebody that's worth saving.
We're not going to discard them.
But when it is the oppressed responding,
they're easily discarded.
They're not worth saving.
No, they're terrorists.
It can't be mental health.
It can't be the response mentally
to having been subjugated
to a bunch of actual oppression.
Nah, it can't be that, right?
I'm just speaking because
as we're witnessing all of this,
you know, there's going to be language used
and that language is not,
it is not used diplomatically.
Right?
Right.